A Guide to the George P. Haw Papers, 1837-1984 (bulk 1870-1905)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
George P. Haw Papers, 1837-1984 (bulk 1870-1905)
The Library of Virginia
43272
1.15 cu. ft. (3 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Joe Kyle, Ashland, 13 June 2007.
Biographical Information
George P. Haw (ca. 1838-1930) of Hanover County, served with the "Hanover Grays", Co. J, 15th Regiment Virginia Infantry during the Civil War. He attended Washington and Lee University after the war and was a lawyer in Richmond and the surrounding Hanover and Henrico Counties, Virginia. His work focused mainly on real estate law.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1837-1984 (bulk 1870-1905), including correspondence, court records, deeds, and receipts documenting aspects of George P. Haw's law practice. The court records, 1867-1915, include judgments, decrees, summons, and writs. Included are numerous deeds, 1858-1918, for land in Hanover and Henrico Counties and Richmond, Virginia. Also included are receipts, 1858-1919, detailing costs and estate settlements. It is likely that correspondence, court records, deeds, and receipts interrelate, but were not maintained together and the exact relationship was not possible to discern.
Of note are incorporation declarations of the Mutual Investment Association of Baltimore City and the Alliance and Industrial Union Manufacturing Co.; marriage certificates of the Blair and Longest families; and a tribute to John H. Timberlake.
Contents List
- Account of Ellen L. Fontaine with L.B. Price, 1879-1887. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Advertisement, c. 1890. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Alliance and Industrial Union Manufacturing Co. incorporation declaration, 1890. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Auction notes, 1901-1916. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Certificate from Home Knowledge Association, 1890. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1837-1876. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1877-1885. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1886-1889. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1890-1894. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1895-1898. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1900-1909. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1911-1940. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1984. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, nd. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Court records (including judgments, suits, summons), 1867-1915. (Folder 15)
- Deeds, 1858-1859. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Deeds, 1860-1869. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Deeds, 1870-1875. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Deeds, 1876-1879. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Deeds, 1880-1884. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Deeds, 1885. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Deeds, 1886. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Deeds, 1887. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Deeds, 1888-1889. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Deeds, 1890. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Deeds, 1891-1892. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Deeds, 1893-1894. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Deeds, 1895. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Deeds, 1896. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Deeds, 1897-1899. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Deeds, 1900-1901. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Deeds, 1902-1903. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Deeds, 1903-1908. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Deeds, 1912-1918. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Deeds/Abstracts of titles, nd. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Marriage certificates, 1865-1890. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Certificate of William Blair and Martha L. Robbins of Crawford County, Pennsylvania (1865) and Samuel L. Longest and Sallie Bosher of Richmond, Virginia (1890).
- Miscellaneous, 1935. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Montana Mining Syndicate stockholder notices, 1896-1900. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Mutual Investment Association of Baltimore City incorporation declaration, 1890. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Notes, miscellaneous, nd. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Occidental Mining Company stockholder notice, 1904. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Petitions, nd. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Photograph, ca. 1900. (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Plats of Hanover County, 1875-1905. (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Receipts, 1858-1879. (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Receipts, 1880-1884. (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Receipts, 1885. (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Receipts, 1886. (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Receipts, 1887. (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Receipts, 1888. (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Receipts, 1889. (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Receipts, 1890. (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Receipts, 1891. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Receipts, 1892. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Receipts, 1893. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Receipts, 1894. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Receipts, 1895. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Receipts, 1896. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Receipts, 1897. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Receipts, 1898. (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Receipts, 1899. (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Receipts, 1900-1902. (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Receipts, 1903-1905. (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Receipts, 1918-1919. (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Receipts, nd. (Box 3, Folder 13)
- John H. Timberlake memorial, nd. (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Wages and effects of a deceased seaman (Frederick C. Brown), 1888. (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Wills, extract of, John Forward, nd. (Box 3, Folder 16)